# **Gautam Rajeev Singh**

Google Certified Professional Data Engineer Python Developer www.singhgautam.com gautamsingh1997@gmail.com linkedin: /singhgautam7

# **About Me**

I am an efficient and confident coding enthusiast with demonstrated experience of working in the backend and database planning. My experience helped me develop expert knowledge of Python. I am highly motivated to continue learning and improving my craft.

# **Educational Background**

SSGI - FET, Junwani, Bhilai (2015 - 2019) Computer Science & Engineering - 70%

K.V. no.1 Raipur (2015) Senior Secondary(12th) - 87.6%

#### **Technical Skills**

- Expert: Django, Python, Flask, DRF
- Intermediate: C++, C, VS Code, Ubuntu, HTML, CSS, GCP
- Learning: React, VueJS

## **Certifications and Achievements**

- Google Cloud Platform Certified Professional Data Engineer
- Designed backend system for an ecommerce business to manage 42k customers at once.
- Diversified my technical experience by creating chat application, wallets, ecommerce application, promo code management system, order management system, microservice architecture etc.
- Integrated third-party APIs like, payment gateway (Razorpay), calling (Ezetap, Twilio), sms (MSG91, BulkSMS), accounts and ledger (Zoho Books), locations (google maps, locus) etc.

## **Work History**

## **SpringML**

Data Engineer

Jan 2022 - Current

- Devoted time to work on Google cloud platform and it's resources
- Utilized Infrastructure as a code tool (like terraform) to seamlessly manage the resource management in cloud.
- Adapted microservice architecture in some projects to increase flexibility.

#### CodeNicely

Software Development Engineer Oct 2019 - Dec 2021

- Developed back-end from scratch on one of CodeNicely's biggest project.
- Fashioned web-applications as per client's demands and expectations.
- Spearheaded a team of 4 people to design and develop projects on different platorms.
- Managed clients personally and noted their feedbacks for delopment and quality assurance
- Mentored new django developers in the company.
- Interviewed new applicants and shortlisted them as per company's requirements.

## BYJU's- The Learning App

Business Development Associate Internship- Jan 2019 - Apr 2019 Fulltime- Jun 2019 - Sep 2019

- Regularly and effectively met warm calling targets, 2.5-3 hours call time per day.
- Accelerated company's growth by achieving a target revenue of 1.5L-2L per week.